Guide to the Sheffield Scientific School, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Administrative Records, 1864-1956; Series III
  - Official Notices
    - 1938-1939 (Box 62, Folder 675)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 62, Folder 676)
    - 1940-1941 (Box 63, Folder 677)
    - 1941-1942 (Box 63, Folder 678)
    - 1942-1943 (Box 63, Folder 679, Box 133)
    - 1940s (Box 63, Folder 680)
    - no date (Box 63, Folder 681)
- Financial, Legal, and Property Records, 1846-1969; Series IV
  Series IV, FINANCIAL, LEGAL, AND PROPERTY RECORDS, is divided into eight sections:
  Historical Papers, 1846-1906
  Legal Matters re: Trustee Property, 1871-1927
  Building Construction and Maintenance, 1892-1929
  Legal Documents re: Funds, 1871-1923
  George St. John Sheffield Bequest,1920-1937
  Amelia Daggett Sheffield Estate, 1936-1937
  The George Sheffield Fund, 1925-1952
  Financial Records and Reports, 1873-1964
  Materials within each of these sections are arranged alphabetically and/or chronologically.
  Historical Papers contains materials relating to the Sheffield Scientific School's early development: correspondence, the Articles of Incorporation of the Board of Trustees and bequest information among others. Because of their size and nature the historical papers were arbitrarily pulled together into a combined chronological and alphabetical subsection. Legal Matters re: Trustee Property contains deeds for land and buildings and agreements for building use by others. Building Construction and Maintenance contains contracts and related papers for construction, renovation and upkeep of the buildings. Legal Documents re: Funds contains materials relating to donations of land and money. Materials in the George St. John Sheffield Bequest section include the will, inventories, correspondence and financial and tax matters. The Amelia Daggett Sheffield Estate section contains materials regarding the estate settlement and distribution: the will., inventories, appraisals and release forms. The George Sheffield Fund material includes correspondence, financial papers and reports summarizing fund supported research from 1938-1952.
  Financial Records and Reports is divided into six subsections:
  Securities Lists, 1882-1937
  Disbursements Reports, 1893-1902
  General Financial Papers, 1881-(1908?)
  Treasurer's Reports, 1890-1964
  External Auditor's Reports, 1931-1947
  Account Books, 1871-1969
  These provide a fairly complete picture of the Sheffield Scientific School's financial development and status.
  - Historical Papers
    - 1846-1869 (Box 64, Folder 682)
    - [illegible] (Box 64)
    - 1870-1879 (Box 64, Folder 683)
    - 1880-1885 (Box 64, Folder 684)
    - Articles of Association of the Board of Trustees of Sheffield Scientific School (original) [See also: folder 695, Incorporation of the Board of Trustees of Sheffield Scientific School: Legislative Act of Incorporation and folder 698, Joseph Earl Sheffield: correspondence re: incorporation and gifts], 1871 February 8 (Box 64, Folder 685)
    - Belknap Prize: correspondence, 1885 August 22 (Box 64, Folder 686)
    - Bills and receipts, 1862-1866 (Box 64, Folder 687)
    - Biology, controversy re: instruction in Sheffield Scientific School and Yale College: correspondence and reports (Box 64, Folder 688)
    - Connecticut General Assembly, Joint Committee on Agriculture: petition of Sheffield Scientific School to the Committee re: agriculture and land grant money, (1890s) (Box 64, Folder 689)
    - Control of Sheffield Scientific School question: legal opinion of Watrous and Daly, etc., 1919 (Box 64, Folder 690)
    - Councillors, Board of: note re: its appointment, (1869?) (Box 64, Folder 691)
    - DuBois, Augustus: contracts and papers relating to his publications which were Trustee property, 1875-1916 (Box 64, Folder 692)
    - Gilman, Daniel C.: resolutions offered to him on his departure to the University of California, 1872 October 9 (Box 64, Folder 693)
    - Graduates from Sheffield Scientific School: list of numbers, 1854-1921 (Box 64, Folder 694)
    - Incorporation of the Board of Trustees of Sheffield Scientific School: Legislative [See also: folder 685, Articles of Association of the Board of Trustees of Sheffield Scientific School (original) and folder 698, Joseph Earl Sheffield: correspondence re: incorporation and gifts], 1882 March 21 (Box 64, Folder 695)
    - Scientific apparatus: bills and receipts sent to Benjamin Silliman, Jr., Circa 1855-1859 (Box 64, Folder 696)
    - Sheffield, Joseph Earl: bills, correspondence and receipts re: construction and equipment purchases for early Sheffield Scientific School buildings, 1858-1862 (Box 64, Folder 697)
    - Sheffield, Joseph Earl: correspondence re: incorporation and gifts [See also: folder 685, Articles of Association of the Board of Trustees of Sheffield Scientific School (original) and folder 695, Incorporation of the Board of Trustees of Shef f ield Scientific School: Legislative Act of Incorporation], 1871, 1881 (Box 64, Folder 698)
    - Yale College, Corporation of: extracts from the records of the Yale College Corporation re: Sheffield Scientific School and scientific education, 1846 August-1873 March (Box 64, Folder 699)
  - Legal Matters re: Trustee Property
    - 187 Church Street: contract with Wallace B. Fern to purchase this property from Sheffield Scientific School Trustees, 1890 February 1 (Box 65, Folder 700)
    - 3 Hillhouse Avenue: property deed, agreement and related papers, 1903, 1948 (Box 65, Folder 701)
    - New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad Company: lease for cable and sidetrack along the Northampton cut, contracts, related papers and blueprint, 1903, 1905 (Box 65, Folder 702)
    - New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad Company: lease of side track constructed by this company, by the Trustees of Sheffield Scientific School, to the Harrison-Hart Company, 1916 September 22 (Box 65, Folder 703)
    - North Sheffield Hall: copy of deed of gift for building and land and a note dated 1961 Jul 5, signed by Charles Hyde Warren, Sheffield Scientific School Director, stating its significance, 1871 February 18 (Box 65, Folder 704)
    - Prospect Street lot: extracts from deed, 1871 May 25 (Box 65, Folder 705)
    - Southern New England Telephone Company: Pole and Lateral Permit at 53-63 Prospect Street, 1927 January 27 (Box 65, Folder 706)
    - United States Government contracts for rental of Sheffield Scientific School buildings during World War I: correspondence, financial material and space allocations, 1918 (Box 65, Folder 707 - 708)
      See also: Series III, boxes 39-40, folders 341-372 (World War I Activities)
  - Building Construction and Maintenance
    - Electrical Laboratory Building: contracts and related papers, 1912 (Box 65, Folder 709)
    - Hammond Laboratory: contract, 1904 (Box 65, Folder 710)
    - Kirkland Hall: contracts and related papers, 1902-1904 (Box 65, Folder 711)
    - Leet Oliver Hall: contracts and related papers, 1907-1908 (Box 65, Folder 712)
    - Mason Laboratory: contracts and related papers, 1909-1911 (Box 65, Folder 713)
    - North Sheffield Hall: renovation contracts with Larkin-Carey Company and related papers, 1929 (Box 65, Folder 714)
    - Utility contracts and related papers: Westinghouse, Church, Kerr and Company for heat and light at Sheffield Scientific School facilities, 1904 (Box 65, Folder 715)
    - Utility contracts and related papers: Westinghouse Electric and Manufacturing Company for a turbo generating unit and switch board, 1916-1917 (Box 65, Folder 716)
    - Winchester Hall: specifications from architects J. C. Cady and Company, 1892-1893 (Box 65, Folder 717)
  - Legal Documents re: Funds
    - Scott, James Alvin (1877s): will and papers relating to a bequest, 1921, 1923 (Box 66, Folder 718)
    - Sheffield, Joseph E.: papers relating to the distribution of his estate, 1871-1889 (Box 66, Folder 719)
    - Sheffield Loan Fund: memo, 1887 (Box 66, Folder 720)
    - Sheffield, Paul King: quit-claim deed of land in Illinois to the Board of Trustees of Sheffield Scientific School, 1886 September 28 (Box 66, Folder 721)
    - Tuttle, Howard B. and Frederick W. Vanderbilt: correspondence with Sheffield Scientific School Trustees re: agreement of donation of funds, 1914-1921 (Box 66, Folder 722)
    - Vanderbilt, Frederick W. [See: folder 722, Howard B. Tuttle and Frederick W. Vanderbilt: correspondence with Sheffield Scientific School Trustees re: agreement of donation of funds]
  - George St. John Sheffield Bequest
    - Last will and testament, 1920 January 27 (Box 67, Folder 723)
    - Inventory, appraisal and legal preliminary notice of estate, 1925 April 6 (Box 67, Folder 724)
    - Correspondence, 1929 May 3 (Box 67, Folder 725)
    - Executor's accounts: cash book and journal, 1924-1926 (Box 67, Folder 726)
    - Accounts, executor's ledger, 1924-1926 (Box 67, Folder 727)
    - Accounts of the Trustees: cash book, journal and inventory, 1925-1937 (Box 67, Folder 728)
    - Accounts of the Trustees: ledger, 1925-1937 (Box 67, Folder 729)
    - Balance sheets, income tax forms and related financial papers
      - 1924-1926 (Box 67, Folder 730)
      - 1927-1930 (Box 67, Folder 731)
      - 1931-1937 (Box 67, Folder 732)
    - Trust terminal statement: first draft and final copy, 1937 (Box 67, Folder 733)
  - Amelia Daggett Sheffield Estate
    - Last will and testament and disposition of household articles, 1936 July 2 (Box 68, Folder 734)
    - Inventories and appraisals of household furniture and effects and real estate, 1937 April-May (Box 68, Folder 735)
    - Release forms and receipt forms from the distribution of the estate, 1937 (Box 68, Folder 736)
    - Financial and legal papers re: settlement of the estate, 1937 (Box 68, Folder 737)
  - George Sheffield Fund
    - Excerpts from the will of George St. John Sheffield re: fund in memory of his two sons, Joseph Earl Sheffield (1894) and George Sheffield (1894s), 1925 January 30 (Box 68, Folder 738)
    - Grant correspondence, financial data and reports
      - 1938-1939 (Box 68, Folder 739)
      - 1939-1940 (Box 68, Folder 740)
      - 1940-1941 (Box 68, Folder 741)
      - 1941-1942 (Box 68, Folder 742)
      - 1942-1943 (Box 68, Folder 743)
      - 1943-1944 (Box 68, Folder 744)
      - 1944-1945 (Box 68, Folder 745)
      - 1945-1946 (Box 68, Folder 746)
      - 1946-1947 (Box 68, Folder 747)
      - 1947-1948 (Box 68, Folder 748)
      - 1948-1949 (Box 68, Folder 749)
      - 1949-1950 (Box 68, Folder 750)
      - 1950-1951 (Box 68, Folder 751)
      - 1951-1952 (Box 68, Folder 752)
  - Financial Records and Reports
    - Securities Lists
      - 1882-1884 (Box 69, Folder 753)
      - 1887-1890 (Box 69, Folder 754)
      - 1891-1895 (Box 69, Folder 755)
      - 1896-1900 (Box 69, Folder 756)
      - 1901-1903 (Box 69, Folder 757)
      - 1904-1906 (Box 69, Folder 758)
      - 1937 (Box 69, Folder 759)
    - Disbursements Reports
      - 1893-1894 (Box 69, Folder 760)
      - 1894-1895 (Box 69, Folder 761)
      - 1895-1896 (Box 69, Folder 762)
      - 1896-1897 (Box 69, Folder 763)
      - 1897-1898 (Box 69, Folder 764)
      - 1898-1899 (Box 69, Folder 765)
      - 1899-1900 (Box 69, Folder 766)
      - 1901-1902 (Box 69, Folder 767)
      - 1902-1903 (Box 69, Folder 768)
    - General Financial Papers
      - Balance sheets, estimated expense sheets and trial balance sheets, 1880-1885 (Box 69, Folder 769)
      - Balance sheets, estimated expense sheets, ledger balances and recapitulation sheets, 1886-1889 (Box 69, Folder 770)
      - Balance sheets, ledger balances, trial balance sheets, 1890-1892 (Box 69, Folder 771)
      - Balance sheets, ledger balances, 1893-1894 (Box 69, Folder 772)
      - Ledger balances, 1895-1896 (Box 69, Folder 773)
      - Abstract of income, ledger balances, Sheffield Scientific School Trustee property and real estate, trial balance sheets, 1897 (Box 69, Folder 774)
      - Abstract of income, estimate of income, initial balance sheet, trial balance sheet, 1898 (Box 69, Folder 775)
      - Balance sheets, trial balance sheets, 1899-1900 (Box 69, Folder 776)
      - Report of Sheffield Scientific School finances: drafts and notes, Circa 1908 (Box 69, Folder 777)
    - Treasurer's Reports
      - 1890-1891 (Box 69, Folder 778)
      - 1891-1892 (Box 69, Folder 779)
      - 1896-1897 (Box 69, Folder 780)
      - 1898-1899 (Box 69, Folder 781)
      - 1899-1900 (Box 69, Folder 782)
      - 1900-1901 (Box 69, Folder 783)
      - 1901-1902 (Box 69, Folder 784)
      - 1902-1903 (Box 69, Folder 785)
      - 1903-1904 (Box 70, Folder 786)
      - 1904-1905 (Box 70, Folder 787)
      - 1930-1931 (Box 70, Folder 788)
      - 1931-1932 (Box 70, Folder 789)
      - 1932-1933 (Box 70, Folder 790)
      - 1933-1934 (Box 70, Folder 791)
      - 1934-1935 (Box 70, Folder 792)
      - 1935-1936 (Box 70, Folder 793)
      - 1936-1937 (Box 70, Folder 794)
      - 1937-1938 (Box 70, Folder 795)
      - 1938-1939 (Box 70, Folder 796)
      - 1939-1940 (Box 70, Folder 797)
      - 1940-1941 (Box 71, Folder 798)
      - 1941-1942 (Box 71, Folder 799)
      - 1942-1943 (Box 71, Folder 800)
      - 1943-1944 (Box 71, Folder 801)
      - 1944-1945 (Box 71, Folder 802)
      - 1945-1946 (Box 71, Folder 803)
      - 1946-1947 (Box 71, Folder 804)
      - 1947-1948 (Box 71, Folder 805)
      - 1948-1949 (Box 71, Folder 806)
      - 1949-1950 (Box 71, Folder 807)
      - 1950-1951 (Box 71, Folder 808)
      - 1951-1952 (Box 71, Folder 809)
      - 1952-1953 (Box 71, Folder 810)
      - 1953-1954 (Box 71, Folder 811)
      - 1954-1955 (Box 71, Folder 812)
      - 1959-1960 (Box 71, Folder 813)
      - 1960-1961 (Box 71, Folder 814)
      - 1961-1962 (Box 71, Folder 815)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 71, Folder 816)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 71, Folder 817)
    - External Auditor's Reports
      - 1931-1932, 1933-1934 (Box 72, Folder 818)
      - 1934-1935, 1936-1937 (Box 72, Folder 819)
      - 1938-1939, 1940-1941 (Box 72, Folder 820)
      - 1941-1942, 1943-1944 (Box 72, Folder 821)
      - 1944-1945 (Box 72, Folder 822)
      - 1946-1947 (Box 72, Folder 823)
    - Account Books
      - Cash (disbursements, expenditures) journal, 1919-1928 (Box 73, Folder 824)
      - Cash (disbursements, expenditures) journal, 1928-1940 (Box 73, Folder 825)
      - Cash disbursements journal, 1953-1969 (Box 74, Folder 826 - 827)
      - Cash receipts register, 1919-1927 (Box 75, Folder 828)
      - Cash receipts register, 1927-1940 (Box 75, Folder 829)
      - Cash receipts register, 1940-1953 (Box 76, Folder 830)
      - Cash receipts register, 1953-1969 (Box 76, Folder 831)
      - Day book, 1912-1915 (Box 77, Folder 832)
    - Journal and Cash Books
      - 1871 Jul 29 - 1901 Jul 31 (Box 77, Folder 833)
      - 1871 Jul 29 - 1901 Aug 1 (Box 77, Folder 834)
      - 1901 Aug 1 - 1908 Jul 31 (Box 78, Folder 835 - 836)
      - 1908 Aug 1 - 1927 Jun 30 (Box 78, Folder 837)
      - 1934 Jul - 1950 Jun 30 (Box 78, Folder 838)
    - Ledgers
      - General, 1871-1908 (Box 79, Folder 839)
      - General, 1908-1934 (Box 79, Folder 840)
      - General, 1929-1934 (Box 80, Folder 841)
      - General, 1934-1940 (Box 80, Folder 842 - 843)
      - General ledger and journal, 1940-1953 (Box 81, Folder 844 - 845)
      - General ledger and journal, 1941-1969 (Box 81, Folder 846 - 848)
      - Funds, 1934-1969 (Box 82, Folder 849)
      - Investments, 1955, 1956-1958 (Box 82, Folder 850)
      - Securities, 1920s-1950s (Box 82, Folder 851 - 856)
      - Securities, 1940-1960 (Box 82, Folder 857 - 859)
- Silliman Lectures, Series V
  Endowed in 1901, the Silliman Memorial Lectureship funded an annual series of lectures "the general tendency of which may be such as will illustrate the presence and wisdom of God as manifested in the Natural and Moral World." After presentation, the guest expanded his material into book form to be published by the Sheffield Scientific School. Series V, SILLIMAN LECTURES 1906, 1911-1956, contains the administrative data compiled by the Silliman Lecture Committee, Materials include correspondence suggesting lecturers, invitations, acceptances, declinations, Corporation votes affirming lecturers, correspondence discussing lecture topics and material re: publication of the manuscripts. See Appendix 2 for a list of Silliman Lecturers.
  The materials in Series V are arranged in three sections: Lecturers, Invited Lecturers Who Did Not Accept or Were Unable to Attend, and Suggested Lecturers. The materials within each section are arranged chronologically according to the academic year the Silliman Lecture was given.
  - Lecturers
    - General business, 1917-1922, 1935, 1942 (Box 83, Folder 860)
    - Rutherford, Ernest (1904-1905), 1922 (Box 83, Folder 861)
    - Bateson, William (1907-1908), 1906, 1922 (Box 83, Folder 862)
    - Osler, Sir William (1912-1913), 1911 (Box 83, Folder 863)
    - "Celebration in honor of James Dwight Dana (1913-1914): Adams, Frank Dawson; Coleman, Arthur Philemon; Idding, Joseph Payson; Lindgren, Waldemar; Mathew, William Diller; Ransome, Frederick Leslie; Rice, William North; Walcott, Charles Doolittle (Box 83, Folder 864)
    - Holdane, John Scott (1916-1917), 1913, 1926, 1927 (Box 83, Folder 865)
    - Hadamard, Jacques S. (1919-1920), 1916-1927 (Box 83, Folder 866)
    - Cumont, Franz (1920-1921), 1919-1921 (Box 83, Folder 867)
    - "von Pirquet, Clemens (1921-1922) [See also: Lecturers Invited But Unable to Attend, Albert Enstein], 1921-1923 (Box 83, Folder 868)
    - Krogh, August (1922-1923), 1921-1929 (Box 83, Folder 869)
    - Bohr, Niels (1923-1924) (Box 83, Folder 870)
    - Morgan, Thomas Hunt (1924-1925), 1924-1926 (Box 83, Folder 871)
    - Lewis, Gilbert Newton (1925-1926), 1924-1926 (Box 83, Folder 872)
    - Andrews, Emest Clayton (1926-1927)
      - Memorial lectures, 1924, 1926-1927 (Box 83, Folder 873)
      - Outline of lectures, 1926? (Box 83, Folder 874)
      - Manuscript of Lectures for Publication
        - Lectures I-II: typescript (Box 83, Folder 875)
        - Lecture III: autograph manuscript (Box 83, Folder 876)
        - Lecture III: typescript (Box 83, Folder 877)
        - Lecture IV: autograph manuscript (Box 83, Folder 878)
        - Lecture IV: typescript (Box 84, Folder 879-880)
    - Henderson, L. J. (1927-1928) (Box 84, Folder 881)
    - Weiland, Heinrick (1930-1931), 1929-1933 (Box 84, Folder 882)
    - Richardson, Owen Williams (1931-1932), 1931-1934 (Box 84, Folder 883)
    - Spemann, Hans (1933-1934), 1930-1933 (Box 84, Folder 884)
    - Daly, Reginald Alsworth (1933-1934), 1932-1934 (Box 84, Folder 885)
    - Hubble, Edwin Silliman (1935-1936), 1934-1936 (Box 84, Folder 886)
    - Watson, David (1936-1939), 1934-1950 (Box 84, Folder 887)
    - Chibnall, Albert C. (1938-1939), 1935-1939 (Box 84, Folder 888)
    - Goldschmidt, Richard B. (1939-1940), 1937-1940 (Box 84, Folder 889)
    - Cohn, Edward Joseph (1946-1947), 1944-1954 (Box 84, Folder 890)
    - See: folder 618, Centennial Celebration, Silliman Lecture Committee
    - Harrison, Ross Granville (1948-1949), 1938-1949 (Box 84, Folder 891)
    - Fermi, Enrico (1949-1950), 1948-1951 (Box 84, Folder 892)
    - Urey, Harold C. (1950-1951), 1949-1955 (Box 84, Folder 893)
    - Petterson, Bans (1951-1952), 1951-1954 (Box 85, Folder 894)
    - Cori, Carl F. (1952-1953) (Box 85, Folder 895)
    - Granit, Ragner (1953-1954), 1953-1956 (Box 85, Folder 896)
  - Invited Lecturers Who Did Not Accept or Were Unable to Attend
    - Fisher, Emil and Eduard Buchner (1912-1913), 1911 (Box 85, Folder 897)
    - Gregorie, V. (1915-1916), 1914-1916 (Box 85, Folder 898)
    - Eddington, Arthur (1928-1929, 1931-1932), 1927, 1930 (Box 85, Folder 899)
    - Einstein, Albert (1921-1922), 1920-1921 (Box 85, Folder 900)
    - Fowler, Alfred (1928-1929) (Box 85, Folder 901)
    - Jeans, James H. (1928-1929), 1927-1928 (Box 85, Folder 902)
    - Rutherford, Sir Ernest (1923, 1934-1935), 1933-1934 (Box 85, Folder 903)
    - Sherrington, Charles S. (1929-1930), 1928-1929 (Box 85, Folder 904)
    - Terman, Lewis Madison (1937-1938), 1934-1937 (Box 85, Folder 905)
    - Harrison, Ross Granville (1940-1941?), 1938-1940 (Box 85, Folder 906)
  - Suggested Lecturers
    - 1914-1917, 1919-1921 (Box 85, Folder 907)
    - Rettger, Leo Frederick (1920): correspondence re: delivering two lectures in fall of 1920 to promote "Transformation of Intestinal Flora" (Box 85, Folder 908)
- Student Life, 1901-1949; Series VI
  Series VI, STUDENT LIFE, is organized into three sections:
  Fraternities, 1919-1948
  Student Council Records, 1910-1942
  Young Men's Christian Association Records, 1907-1914
  Material in the Fraternities section includes correspondence, prize information and discussion of discipline problems, The Student Council Records contains constitutions, correspondence, social business, honor code examinations and discipline. In 1932-1933, the Student Council began to serve both the Sheffield Scientific School and the newly created School of Engineering. The Young Men's Christian Association Records consists of the minutes of the Executive Committee and general membership meetings and financial business.
  The materials within the Fraternities and Student Council sections are arranged alphabetically. The materials within the Young Men's Christian Association section are organized by form.
  - Fraternities
    - Cloister Club, The, 1932-1934 (Box 86, Folder 909)
    - Colony, The, 1921-1922, 1933-1934 (Box 86, Folder 910)
    - Fraternity Scholarship Prize, 1920-1921 (Box 86, Folder 911)
    - Fraternity Scholarship Prize, 1921-1929 (Box 86, Folder 912)
    - Fraternity Scholarship Prize, 1930-1948 (Box 86, Folder 913)
    - Franklin Ball, 1920, 1933-1936 (Box 86, Folder 914)
    - General information, 1915, 1918, 1933-1940 (Box 86, Folder 915)
    - Sachem Hall, 1933-1936 (Box 86, Folder 916)
    - St. Anthony Club, 1933-1943 (Box 86, Folder 917)
    - St. Elmo Club, 1920, 1933-1943 (Box 86, Folder 918)
    - Scroll and Compass, 1923-1933 (Box 86, Folder 919)
    - Vernon Hall, 1933-1943 (Box 86, Folder 920)
    - York Hall, 1930-1943 (Box 86, Folder 921)
  - Student Council Records
    - Constitution, 1910-1921 (Box 87, Folder 922)
    - Constitution for Sheffield Scientific School and the School of Engineering joint council, 1933, 1935, 1939 (Box 87, Folder 923)
    - Correspondence
      - 1923-1924, 1927-1928 (Box 87, Folder 924)
      - 1928-1929 (Box 87, Folder 925)
      - 1930-1931 (Box 87, Folder 926)
      - 1932-1934 (Box 87, Folder 927)
      - 1936-1937 (Box 87, Folder 928)
      - 1937-1938 (Box 87, Folder 929)
      - 1938-1939 (Box 87, Folder 930)
      - 1939-1940 (Box 87, Folder 931)
      - 1940-1941 (Box 87, Folder 932)
      - 1941-1942 (Box 87, Folder 933)
      - 1943-1949 (Box 87, Folder 934)
    - Form letters and blank forms (Box 87, Folder 935)
    - Freshman, 1923, 1927 (Box 87, Folder 936)
    - Honor system, 1925 (Box 87, Folder 937)
    - Interhouse agreement of Sheffield Scientific School and Engineering School, revised (Box 87, Folder 938)
    - Interhouse Council Constitution (Box 87, Folder 939)
    - Yale College (Box 87, Folder 940)
  - Young Men's Christian Association
    - Minutes and notes, 1901 April - 1914 March (Box 88, Folder 941)
    - Treasurer's book, 1913-1916 (Box 88, Folder 942)
- Student Papers, 1877-1909; Series VII
  Series VII, STUDENT PAPERS 1877-1911, contains unpublished these submitted by students applying for a Bachelor of Philosophy or an advanced degree. Most of the papers date from 1895 to 1905. The papers deal with scientific or engineering topics; most include plates, diagrams and reproductions.
  The papers are organized alphabetically by author.
  Chang, Tatsemg, "An Outline of the Theory of Electromagnetic Waves" 22pp, box 89, folder 960 was reported missing in April 2015.